GREGORY MALONE

2125 Sandbur Lane • Leander, TX 78641 • (512) 961-0321 • atx76dragon@yahoo.com www.linkedin.com/in/gregory-malone

SUMMARY

Inventory management professional and entry-level full stack developer with a Lean Six Sigma Green Belt and experience across continuous improvement and vendor management. Key strengths include facilitating interdepartmental communication, identifying opportunities for operational improvements, and fostering strategic vendor relationships. Proactive leader committed to championing team success.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, TX

Full Stack Flex Web Development Certificate (Expected 2021)

Southwest School of Electronics

Austin, TX

Associate of Occupational Studies (2001)

SKILLS PROFILE

Tools: Jira, jQuery, MySQL, GitHub, Salesforce, Power BI, Slack, Teams,

SharePoint, Share Directory, Heroku, Agile

Systems: SourceDay, Microsoft Dynamics 365 Business Central

Frameworks/Languages: Bootstrap CSS, Materialize CSS, Node.js, Express.js, HTML, JavaScript

Certifications: Lean Six Sigma Green Belt (2016)

MS Excel (2012)

EXPERIENCE

2009 – 2020 EVERI Games Austin, TX

Specialist, Asset Inventory Management

2019 - 2020

- Oversaw the procurement of premium products, inventory and vendor management, and continuous improvement for a producer of world-class gaming products
- Facilitated field service work requests with vendors, and fostered positive working relationships through regular communication and updates, leading to an increase in the on-time delivery of products
- Collaborated with the warehouse and vendors to develop more efficient and consistent packaging and palletizing solutions, leading to quicker product receipt and more efficient storage
- Established lean inventory management practices, reducing aged inventory and the number of drop shipments, which contributed to an increase in quarterly revenue by \$15M
- Developed and implemented reports in Power BI to consolidate current order data and statuses, supporting
 more efficient weekly inventory management reviews and providing more reliable information to vendors to
 help them meet lead times

Specialist, Continuous Improvement

2017 - 2019

 Collaborated across departments to identify and address process issues by performing cost-benefit analyses, assigning priority levels, developing tooling/improvements, facilitating testing, and providing training

- Led an initiative to implement an OPI (Order Processing Issues) tool in Salesforce, enabling a single tool to capture and track internal and external order processing and leading to increased efficiency in addressing order issues and data reporting
- Developed a plan to create automated reports in Power BI for each department to replace the material
 planning spreadsheet, reducing time spent manually entering data and providing each department with timely
 updates to guide planning
- Improved visibility of order shipments for field technicians by identifying a strategic opportunity to add Salesforce order fields to automate shipping notifications, replacing the Shipping department's manual spreadsheets and manual inputs/outputs, saving multiple departments more than 40 hours per week
- Served as a liaison between the Engineering Services department and other departments throughout the organization to facilitate regular communication and promote continuous improvement efforts for process and tooling efficiency
- Reduced the used parts recurring revenue loss from \$25M to \$17M over 3 quarters by developing a plan to improve the tagging, packaging, and product return processes, utilizing a Kanban system in the warehouse for products returned to inventory and collaborating to send used stock on new orders

Quality Control Inspector 2009 – 2017

- Developed quality inspection documentation to guide the inspection and approval of products, implemented corrective actions, and audited products from vendors
- Gathered and analyzed daily metrics, and reported results at monthly meetings to identify root causes of any ongoing issues
- Regularly collaborated with the customer-facing team to identify ongoing points of frustration, investigate underlying causes, and implement corrective actions
- Taught organizational maturity principles, visual management, and versatility matrices to managers and employees across departments to improve workflows throughout the organization
- Reviewed documentation and process verification for orders in production, and performed the final quality inspection